<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Home | holon]]></title>
  <link href="http://abelsan.github.com/blog/categories/home/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://abelsan.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-31T12:06:56-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://abelsan.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[abel sanchez]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[abel@mit.edu]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Network Upgrade for Home Cloud]]></title>
    <link href="http://abelsan.github.com/blog/2013/05/01/network-upgrade-for-home-cloud/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-01T21:59:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://abelsan.github.com/blog/2013/05/01/network-upgrade-for-home-cloud</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently put together a <a href="/blog/2013/05/01/building-a-home-cloud/">home cloud</a>. Of course, now I need to upgrade my home networking. None of my Ethernet cables support gigabit and my router is two orders of magnitude behind current capabilities. It does not support jumbo frames either.</p>

<p>With recommendations from colleagues, I went to newegg and purchased a new batch of networking equipment.</p>

<p><a href="http://mit.edu/doval/www/assets/img/blog/networking_equipment.jpg">
<img src="http://mit.edu/doval/www/assets/img/blog/networking_equipment_500.jpg">
</a></p>

<p>Most home Internet service is delivered through cable companies. Luckily, in my area I can get FIOS, fiber directly to the house. As great as that is, the default installation converts to coaxial cabling using the Optical Network Terminal (ONT) at the house.  Doing some more research, I found the ONT could use Ethernet instead of coaxial.</p>

<p>I had the fun experience of calling tech support and asking, “Can you change my ONT’s connection to the router from coax to Ethernet? Oh, while you are at it, I also need you to break the router’s DHCP lease.” It took a few tries but Kudos to FIOS tech support; they were knowledgeable and on the ball.</p>

<p>After running cable through the house, installing my new router, testing the connections, and making the ONT switch to Ethernet I was up and running.</p>

<p>I am very happy. My internal transfer speeds are screaming fast.</p>

<p>What is taking the most time is integrating 10 years of data. Most of my old drives are brutally slow. I am currently transferring data from two old external drives. The transfer is in its 38th hour!</p>

<p>Once I am done with the transfers, I will the face the scary task of sorting through the data and giving it some sensible structure. I am living my own personal Big Data challenge (grin).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building a Home Cloud]]></title>
    <link href="http://abelsan.github.com/blog/2013/05/01/building-a-home-cloud/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-01T19:36:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://abelsan.github.com/blog/2013/05/01/building-a-home-cloud</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I knew it was coming. Over the past 10 years. I have been collecting data in CDs, DVDs, external drives, old machines, memory sticks, SD cards, you name it, I have it.</p>

<p>Finally, I reached a crisis point. I had data spread over a multitude of devices in addition to Dropbox, Google Drive, Amazon’s Cloud Drive, and SkyDrive.</p>

<p>I needed to build a proper storage solution. I needed to bring together all of my data into one location. I needed to integrate years of research data, books, publications, proposals, lecture materials, talks, designs, source code, email, graphics files, among many more.</p>

<p>I looked at several offerings in the market. I was looking for a minimum of 10 terabytes. I also wanted redundant drives for recovery. I wanted to gracefully survive drive failures – hot swappable being the ideal. Furthermore, considering I would be working on a lot of the data, I wanted good performance and transfer rates. Taking the previous requirements into account, my short list included ReadyNAS, Synology, QNAP, LaCie, and Asustor.</p>

<p>In the end I choose Synology, the DS413 model. Mainly because the reviews touted the simple setup – they were right.</p>

<p>The installation and setup was a breeze. It took me about 20 minutes to load my drives and fire up the NAS</p>

<p><a href="http://mit.edu/doval/www/assets/img/blog/home_cloud.jpg">
<img src="http://mit.edu/doval/www/assets/img/blog/home_cloud_500.jpg">
</a></p>

<p>In my next entry I will talk about <a href="/blog/2013/05/01/network-upgrade-for-home-cloud">upgrading my home network</a> to improve data access.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
